emcp.com 2019-02-18

# EMC School

_Last updated: 07/28/2015_

### Privacy Policy Applicable to Use of the Website by Schools, School Districts and Their Students

EMC School ("EMC") recognizes the importance of safeguarding the personal information provided to us by the users of our website (the "Website". EMC has implemented this Privacy Policy to govern the use of personally identifiable information and/or personal data that it collects via the Website (the "Personal Information") from the applicable schools and school districts and each of their respective personnel and agents (the "the School/School District") and from K12students (and the parents and guardians of such students) of the applicable School District (collectively, the "Students", and along with the School District, the "School/School District Users") when School District Users communicate electronically with the Website via online classrooms, email or otherwise. This Privacy Policy does not govern Personal Information collected from any other source or in any other manner.

In the event that we make changes to this Privacy Policy, you can visit the page that you're reading now and refer to the "Last Updated" date at the top of this page to learn when this Policy was last revised.

**This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the Terms and Conditions of Use of the Website.**

**This Privacy Policy explains how School District Users' information and data is used:**

  * Collection and Use of Information 
    * Parental Consent
    * Registration and User Profiles
    * Collection of Personal Information
    * Use of Cookies
    * Collection and Use of Aggregate Data
    * Collection and Use of Performance Data
    * Use of Aggregate Data
    * Use of Personal Information 
      * Disclosure of Personal Information within EMC and to its Affiliates 
      * Disclosure of Personal Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties 
    * User Profiles
    * Acquisition of Business
    * With Consent
  * Links to Other Sites
  * Information Storage and Protection
  * Options to Review and Opt-Out Choices
  * Changes in Policy
  * To Contact Us

**Collection and Use of Information**

**Parental Consent for Students' Use of the Website**

EMC will presume/require that the applicable school or school district has obtained the consent of the parent or legal guardian of all Students ("students") using the Website. By arranging with EMC for Students to access and use the Website, (i) students and their parents and legal guardians, schools and school districts are consenting to the provisions of this Privacy Policy, including the use of Personal Information and Performance Data by EMC in the manner described above; and (ii) schools and school districts are accepting responsibility for obtaining any and all necessary parental consents for EMC to collect and use the Personal Information and Performance Data in the ways described in this policy.

COPPA is a regulation that requires parental consent for the online collection of information about users under 13. Any school administering the Website acknowledges and agrees that it is solely responsible for compliance with COPPA, including, but not limited to, obtaining parental consent concerning collection of students' personal information used in connection with the provisioning and use of the Services by the Customer and End Users.

For parents and legal guardians of K12 students: If you have any questions concerning use of the Website, and/or with respect to the collection and use of information or materials uploaded to this site, please contact an authorized representative at the School District.

**Registration and User Profiles**

In connection with the registration process, each School District User will provide user profile information as instructed by the School District. User profile information may include a user ID and an email address.

When a School District User registers with the School District to use the Website, he or she will also be asked to create a password. This password should not be disclosed to anyone. If a School District User shares his or her password or other Personal Information or Performance Data with others, the School District User shall be responsible for all resulting actions, including actions taken in the name of the School District User's account. Therefore, if a School District User's password has been compromised for any reason, the School District User's (and in the case of students, such student's parent and/or legal guardian) should immediately notify an authorized representative at the School District.

**Collection of Personal Information**

Once a School District User is registered to use the Website, a user ID will be created for the School District User and Personal Information will be collected for such User, *[[including name and email address]]*. You do not have an option to hide your user ID from others. All use of user IDs must conform to any requirements set out in the Website's [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://www.emcp.com/terms-of-use). Personal Information may also be provided when a School District User uploads certain materials to the Website, such as videos of the School District User.

**Use of Cookies and Plug-ins**

The Website uses a web browser feature called a "cookie". A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to a user's hard drive when the user visits the site. A cookie can't read data off a user's hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. A user may disable or adjust a browser's acceptance of cookies by looking within the settings and/or preferences within that user's web browser. Please note that if a user disables cookies, the user may not be able to take advantage of certain aspects of a website's interactive features. The Website also uses plug-ins. A plug-in is a piece of software that the user downloads into the user's web browser that allows certain web-based software to operate. In order to interact on the Website, School District Users must install certain plug-ins.

Cookies are used on the Website to recognize visitors when they are on the site. Cookies enable the School District Users' online visits to be customized. For instance, cookies can be used to track and target our users' activities, and alert users to new features. We may also evaluate our content and services and tailor our School District Users' experiences based on other information we collect such as IP addresses, pixel tags, and the type of Internet browser or operating system you are using. The information so collected may be tied to a specific School District User through the cookie used as described above; however, no one at EMC will be able to determine that it is tied to a personally identified School District User for any purpose and such information will not be tied to any personally identifiable information except as needed to diagnose and/or remedy a problem with the online service.

**Collection and Use of Aggregate Data**

EMC receives and stores certain types of information whenever a School District User interacts with our Website. The Website automatically receives and records information on server logs, including a date/time stamp, the School District User's IP address (which are numbers assigned to a user's computer whenever the user accesses the internet), cookie information, internet service provider (ISP), pages viewed, and content and the media School District User have consumed (e.g., viewed, played, downloaded, uploaded, and shared).

This information is used to gather demographic information on visitors to the Website (such as geographic locations users are visiting from and the time spent on the site), help diagnose problems with the server, administer and improve the Website and analyze usage trends. As part of this use of information, we may provide this aggregate information to the schools and school districts, and may also provide aggregate information to our Affiliates and partners about how school districts (and their students), use the Website. Our "Affiliates" are companies directly or indirectly controlled or owned by us, or companies that directly or indirectly control us, or are under common control with us.

AEMC contracts with non-affiliated third parties/business partners to host the Website and to provide data collection and reports regarding users' activities on the Website. These non-affiliated third parties/business partners use cookies on our behalf and receives information about the School District Users browsing activity and collects information anonymously (meaning without attaching it to any personally identifiable user) and aggregates information such as: student class year and location. These non-affiliated third parties/business partners have agreed not to use this information other than (i) in connection with providing services to us to make our Website more useful and efficient, (ii) as permitted in this Privacy Policy, or (iii) as otherwise permitted by law. In addition, these non-affiliated third parties/business partners are subject EMC's confidentiality policies.

Regardless of whether a School District User (including a student's parent or guardian) has chosen to limit EMC's sharing of Personal Information as collected on the Website, EMC may, without restriction, use, share and disclose aggregated statistics about School District Users, along with specific information concerning individual School District Users that is not Personal Information in any way permitted by applicable law.

**Collection and Use of Performance Data**

When a student uses the Website, a variety of information will be generated concerning that student's skills and performance, such as completed worksheets and exercises (collectively, "Performance Data"). EMC will collect and share students' Performance Data with such students' teachers and other personnel retained by the students' schools and school districts. Such personnel will be able to associate such Performance Data with the specific student to which the Data relates.

EMC will also aggregate Performance Data, and may use, share and disclose such aggregated Performance Data with the schools and school districts and otherwise as permitted by law. For example, EMC may use such aggregated Performance Data for research and product development purposes, and may also share such aggregated Performance Data with EMC's business partners and Affiliates.

**Use of Personal Information**

Personal Information collected about School District Users may be used to manage the Website's interactive functionality, to help improve and enhance the Website experience, by EMC and its Affiliates and non-affiliated third parties/business partners for research and product development purposes, and for compliance with legal and regulatory obligations.

EMC may share Personal Information with our Affiliates as required or permitted by applicable law.

We will also share Personal Information concerning individual students with: (i) the students' teachers and other personnel at the students' schools; (ii) personnel retained by the students' school districts; (iii) the students and those students' parents and legal guardians.

**Disclosure of Personal Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties**

In addition to the above disclosures, EMC may share School District Users' Personal Information, without restriction, with companies and organizations that we retain to perform services for us, such as those that provide data processing, computer software maintenance and development, marketing services, including but not limited to Vidku, Inc., and companies providing professional, legal or accounting advice to EMC. In such situations, EMC requires that these companies and organizations agree to (a) maintain the confidentiality of the Personal Information and (b) limit the use of such Personal Information to the purposes for which it was provided. Finally, under limited circumstances, regardless of whether a School District User has chosen to limit our sharing of his or her Personal Information as collected on the Website, Personal Information may be disclosed to non-affiliated third parties as either permitted by, or to comply with, applicable laws and regulations. For example, Personal Information may be disclosed to comply with investigations by regulatory authorities or enforcement agencies in the United States of America or elsewhere, or to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud. Furthermore, P ersonal Information may be disclosed if there is a reasonable good faith basis to believe that disclosure is required by law, compelled by court order or legal process, or is reasonably necessary and/or appropriate to: (i) protect the rights, property and/or safety of [EMC] or any other person or entity; or (ii) prevent or take action concerning any alleged: (a) illegal activity or (b) breach of the Terms and Conditions or Privacy Policy of the Website.

**Acquisition of Business**

In the event that EMC or one of its Affiliates is involved in a merger, acquisition, consolidation, restructuring, reorganization, liquidation, sale or similar transaction relating to any portion of its business and/or assets, or in the unlikely event that EMC or one of its goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, each School District User hereby acknowledges and agrees that the Website, all data collected on the Website (including Personal Information and Performance Data), and all of EMC's rights under this Privacy Policy may be included in the assets of, and/or transferred pursuant to, such transaction, and that any acquirer or successor (or a third party through bankruptcy) of EMC or one of its Affiliates may continue to use the Personal Information and Performance Data as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If that occurs, EMC will post a notice to such effect on the Website and/or provide notification by any other media or contact method as may be required by applicable laws and regulations.

**With Your Consent**

Except as for the sharing of Personal Information permitted in this Privacy Policy, when EMC seeks to share any Personal Information, EMC will notify the specific School District and the School District will notify those School District Users whose Personal Information it seeks to share, and such School District Users (and in the case of students, such student's parent and/or legal guardian) will be able to elect to refuse consent for the sharing of this information.

**Links to other sites and services**

The Website may contain links to various other sites that may ask to collect user information voluntarily. Please be aware that these other websites may have different privacy policies that may subject users to different privacy practices. Please review the privacy policies of such other websites for information concerning what information is collected on such websites and how it is used.

**LInformation storage and protection**

There are industry standard safeguards in place to protect School District Users' Personal Information, such as the use of firewalls and SSL certificates, and limiting access to such information by company personnel. Personal Information will be stored in databases and servers located in the United States. However, no transmission made through the internet can be made completely secure, and EMC will not be liable for the disclosure of any School District Users' Personal Information or Performance Data that occurs as a result of transmission errors or the actions of any third party.

**Options to review and opt-out**

School District Users (and in the case of students, such students' parents and/or legal guardians) may access, review and, in certain situations, update certain Personal Information and Performance Data, as determined by the School District.

While School District Users may be able to add or update certain information (such as contact information), please note that EMC may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. Additionally, while you may request deletion of by contacting EMC, please note that some information may remain in our records after any such deletion of your account.

As the Website evolves, EMC may offer additional options for School District Users to view and/or edit the information we collect. Please check this Privacy Policy often to make sure you have reviewed the most recent version.

If for any reason you wish to discontinue the use of the Website and have your Personal Information removed from our database, subject to the exceptions noted above, please contact your School District contact.

**Changes in Policy**

From time to time, EMC's Privacy Policy may change. EMC will post changes to the Privacy Policy on the Website. Please review this Privacy Policy often so that you will remain abreast of EMC's current policies. Users of the Website are responsible for making sure they are aware of the provisions of EMC's most current (see the date at the top of this Privacy Policy) Privacy Policy.

**To Contact Us**

We welcome feedback and constructive comments on how we can improve the experience that we offer.

Please be advised that any form of communication sent to the Website, be it ideas, suggestions or any other e-mail, will be considered non-confidential and nonproprietary.

If you have any questions about this online privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with the Website, you can contact:

EMC School  
875 Montreal Way  
St. Paul, MN 55102

1-800-328-1452
